JOHN KELLY

CONTACT

Address: Cheltenham Gloucestershire

GL54 5LJ

Phone: 07494371641

Email: jd.kelly803@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/j

ohnkelly803/

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

https://waltzingintryst.netlify.app/

SKILLS

- Operating System: Windows (10, 11, Server 16, 19), Mac (Sierra, High Sierra, Mojave), Linux (Ubuntu, RHEL, Centos, Fedora, Nix)
- Endpoint Security: (Crowdstrike, MS Defender, Sentinel, Sophos, Meraki)
- O365: (Sharepoint, Teams, Onedrive, PowerBI, Office Suite, O365 Admin)
- Networking: (Azure & AWS SDN, LAN, WAN, TCP/IP, WiFI)
- Azure: (Entra ID (AZAD), Intune, Dynamic Grouping, MFA, Azure Services)
- Patch & assets Management: (Heimdal, Connectwise, Jamf, Solarwinds)
- 3rd party S/w: (Adobe, Egress, Figma, Miro, Axure, Apple Business Manager, Egnyte, Chrome browser Management)
- Scripting: (Powershell, Python, Bash)
- · CICD: (Jenkins)
- Containerization (Docker)
- IaC: (Terraform, Ansible)
- Effective communication
- · Training and Development
- Software diagnostics
- IT troubleshooting
- Career Mentoring
- Supportive leadership within IT team

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seasoned IT Engineer with 20+ years of experience spanning Windows, Mac, Linux, Azure, O365, Intune, Teams, virtualization platforms, and popular security solutions. Consistently ensured peak performance, implemented rigorous security protocols, and maximized user satisfaction across multiple sites. Played a pivotal role in preparing infrastructures and companies for ISO certification. Ensured corporate devices and infrastructure are robust and reliable. By working closely with Information Security, maintained stringent documentation and regular reviews, underpinning the trust our clients place in our technology solutions.

WORK HISTORY

IT Operations Manager, 11/2019 to 09/2023 Arkk Solutions - City of London, London

- Upgraded hardware and software regularly for optimized systems performance, via Heimdal
- Managed Windows 10/11, Windows Server 16/19, Mac & iOS.
- Managed EntralD, Azure Sentinel, Intune, Defender Endpoint, Crowdstrike, Zscaler, O365, & Jamf
- Used Powershell for Automation
- Setup & maintained asset management of entire technological landscape
- Installed new technologies without disrupting workflow.
- Maintained system security through regular testing and servicing.
- Managed technology resources within department budgets.
- Analyzed system and software requirements to meet operational needs.
- Assessed system performance to advise on possible updates and improvements.
- Advised on Information and communications technology policy and process improvements.
- Negotiated cost-efficient prices with vendors for new systems and services.
- Controlled department budgets by sourcing cost-effective solutions.
- Liaised with service users to ascertain necessary system improvements.
- Liaised with service users and business managers to meet computing requirements
- Sourced new and emerging technologies to optimize information services.
- Engaged with external stakeholders, interpreting briefs to develop IT systems within allocated budget.
- Conducted in-depth research into diverse topics to create richlydetailed, factual works.
- Prepared easily understood, clear and complete user manuals and guides for consumers.
- Maintained version history for projects and organised file system.

Netstar MSP - City of London, City of London

- Tracked computer system and network performance to identify root causes of issues.
- Provided prompt support to internal and customer-facing IT infrastructure.
- Installed, configured and maintained high-performing multiplatform technologies.
- Resolved technical faults across varied technologies, including servers, routers and hardware.
- Carried out new hardware installations and updates, keeping systems functional and secure.
- Answered user questions about hardware and software operation to help resolve problems.
- Delivered reliable, high quality technical support to average of 100 users daily.
- Managed and implemented all new software, systems and solutions.
- Installed new software for users and monitored version and patch update requirements.
- Followed technical documentation for accurate installation, maintenance and repair work.
- Established and troubleshot network and data communications systems.
- Investigated, diagnosed and remedied diverse hardware issues within fixed service-level agreements.
- Organised workspaces for employees with computer, monitors and associated cabling or equipment.
- Developed robust patching regime for optimum server, storage, network and desktop environments.
- Distilled complex technical information into easily digestible instructions for end-users.

Lead Support Engineer, 02/2017 to 03/2019 **Dolfin Financial Group** - City of London, City of London

- Installed new software for users and monitored version and patch update requirements.
- Followed technical documentation for accurate installation, maintenance and repair work.
- Answered user questions about hardware and software operation to help resolve problems.
- Carried out new hardware installations and updates, keeping systems functional and secure.
- Prepared equipment for staff use, installing cables, operating systems, and software.
- Tracked computer system and network performance to identify root causes of issues.
- Maintained internet and intranet websites to maximize reliability and usability.
- Used Jira to track support tickets and document actions.
- Offered technical advice to programmers and developers to help optimize designs.
- Distilled complex technical information into easily digestible instructions for end-users.
- Organized workspaces for employees with computer, monitors and associated cabling or equipment.
- Mentored junior engineers, identifying skill gaps, and working towards their career goals

IT Support Engineer, 02/2015 to 02/2017 **Westgroup Investments Limited** - City of London, City of London

- Carried out new hardware installations and updates, keeping systems functional and secure.
- Installed new software for users and monitored version and patch update requirements.
- Monitored and performed hardware and software upgrades to network servers, including operating systems and applications.
- Troubleshot network issues and provided rapid solutions to limit downtime.
- Answered user questions about hardware and software operation to help resolve problems.
- Configured routers, switches and firewalls to deploy and support LAN, WAN and wireless networks.
- Prepared equipment for staff use, installing cables, operating systems, and software.

Head Bartender, 08/2013 to 01/2015 **Ain't Nothin' But Blues Bar** - London, London

- Performed bar closing duties, thoroughly cleaning, sanitising and replenishing stock.
- Oversaw bar recordkeeping and stocktaking for organised and profitable operations.
- Provided efficient food and drinks service for high levels of customer satisfaction.
- Collected cash payments, processing and providing correct change and receipts using Point Of Sale (POS) systems.
- Engaged with guests to create positive rapport, encouraging loyalty and repeat visits.
- Served guests spirits, lagers and stouts at bar.
- Maintained bar stocks, replenishing daily as necessary.
- Set up bar area daily with clean furniture, supplies and beverage stock for typical bar demands.
- Prepared mixed drinks and poured wine, beer and non-alcoholic beverages within target service timeframes.
- Maintained knowledge of drinks promotions, pricing and menu changes, offering customers up-to-date, reliable advice.
- Created range of alcoholic and non-alcoholic mixed drinks for establishment guests.
- Retained in-depth bar and menu item knowledge, providing expert recommendations to suit guest taste.
- Coordinated daily replenishment and stock resets to maintain organised, tidy bar space.
- Prepared for closing by cleaning bar area and announcing last orders.
- Created friendly, welcoming atmosphere to encourage positive guest experiences, prolonging visits to increase profitability.

EDUCATION

RHCSA: Red hat Certified Systems administration, 05/2024 - Current

At Home - Winchcombe

Devops Bootcamp: Devops Bootcamp, 09/2023 - Current **Tech World with Nana** - At home

HOBBIES AND INTEREST

• Tinkering with Linux & python

- Working at charity farm for kids with special needs
- Workingout

REFERENCES

References available upon request.